ANTHONY BERRY

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

linkedin.com/in/anthonyberry1 - anthonyjberry1@gmail.com - 347.314.7815

OBJECTIVE

During my 10-year tenure in the military, I learned how to implement strategy at a large scale and problem solve mission-critical issues. I am seeking to apply that knowledge, as well as my technical skills, to build solutions that will impact the future. In my spare time, I am passionate about providing service to my community and have worked independently as a Homeless Advocate since 2017 to deliver food and care packages to those in need.

EXPERIENCE

Amazon Web Services / SDE Apprentice Mar 2019 - Apr 2020

Designed and implemented a method for handing off encrypted information between services using AWS SNS, SQS and using Scala for millions of bills. Identified and managed key issues impacting the underlying service powering AWS Cost Explorer by creating trouble ticket dashboards using Ruby. Enhanced the team's Apache Spark UI application to enable improved monitoring of active Spark jobs. Trusted to fix high-risk, security-impacting bugs.

Hyxus, INC / Software QA Tester Intern Feb 2018 - Apr 2018

Drove improvements and operational efficiency for software applications by identifying, documenting, and reporting 25+ bugs via Pivotal Tracker. Partnered closely with cross-functional stakeholders to create test plans, test cases and test scripts. Drove improvements to the application user experience and performance, which led to a successful launch.

US ARMY / Program Manager / QA Engineer / Diagnostic Engineer Mar 2005 - Oct 2015

Led logistics for over 3,500 personnel and managed an inventory of sensitive items and weapons, valued at over \$5mm. Instructed and evaluated over 200 soldiers performing preventative weapons maintenance, and pre-marksmanship. Owned diagnosis of failed parts, accelerated replacements, and facilitated on-time delivery.

EDUCATION

B.S, Information SystemsBellevue College Bellevue, WA Sept. 2016 – Present

Code Fellows Software Development Bootcamp Seattle, WA

2019

Leadership & Management Development Course

Army Logistics University
Beginner (2012), Intermediate (2014)

KEY SKILLS

Languages: Java, Scala, Ruby, SQL, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS (familiarity with React and C#)

AWS Services: EC2, Elasticsearch, Elastic MapReduce (EMR), SNS, SQS, CloudFormation, CloudWatch, Lambda, IAM

PROJECTS

Hero Wars | JavaScript, HTML, CSS | https://github.com/team-nada/hero-wars-fe

Developed a spin on the classic game of War where players are dealt 5 cards and each card is tested against the computers card to determine the winner. Integrated a superhero API to populate card with character data

Global-Chat | React.js, HTML, CSS | https://github.com/global-chat/global-translate-frontend

Developed a chatroom application where each user's screen is customized depending on the language selected. Implemented user login and used AWS DynamoDB to store users' account information.